Hello.
Welcome back.
In this lesson, we are going to see how to configure the S.P.I.
So I've started a new project.
As you can see, we can start off by selecting DSP.
I come over here.
Where do we find SPOG connectivity?
We can start with S.P.I one click over here to expand it.
I'm going to select Full Duplex.
And it's selected the, um, the three pins required is squaddie clock the so when Dendi Mozi, as you
can see from here.
So I'm just gonna come to clock configuration and then change 260 megahertz so that we all have the
same clock, including those with the Air Force.
Your reports.
So change over here to 16.
And I hope I can get 16 on both off my clock buses if I don't.
I would have to fiddle with it more.
Okay.
It would be to time a clock 16 if every one time I was 16.
We are good.
So we can come back to penult and configuration and then I'll come to systems for you over here.
Okay.
S.P.I, he's already selected.
So I come to the parameters set in tab over here and then I'm going to pull this up like this.
So over here we can leave most of the options the same.
The pre-schooler here basically is just like a pre-schooler and a timer.
It's the number we pass.
Yeah, it's used to divide the frequency.
So our sixteen gigahertz will be divided by two and we end up with eight megahertz and the board rate
becomes eight megabits per second.
I'm gonna reduce this further.
I'm going to put it around one megabits per second.
Therefore also like to eight over here.
Um, yeah, I'm, I'm putting around two megabits so I select eight.
If I select 16 is gonna give me one megabit, which is a thousand kilobits per second.
So I select eight over here like this.
Next, we go to the GPL, your tub and ensure that we are running.
We run in at high speed.
So the GPA sets is let's see, this is the clock line.
Let's see, well, we have maximum, very high.
What is the one we have it set at high C?
Okay.
Cuba makes her set it for us.
Very high, very high, very high.
And the older version of Cuba makes you.
You would have a drop down.
You would have another window that allows you to change the speed.
But we want them all to be at high speed.
We can go ahead and generate our quote or come to the generator over here and then I'll give my project
a anymore call this S.P.I pole.
Cause we're going to see how to use interrupt and other methods.
There's the pulling method and then I'm going to select it to train over here.
Steam 32 Kubi the E.
Click over here to generate.
So there's a project we can take a look at the generated code.
It's very similar to all the other peripherals we've seen thus far.
It has a basically a handle.
And they handle this very similar to these.
You are to actually got an instance, the mode, the direction, data size, Klok polarity, clockface,
poudre to pre-schooler, et cetera.
So this is it.
So we're gonna start off by creating two global two global arrays.
We shall use them as buffers.
We show have a transmit buffer and receive buffer.
And we're going to send data from the transmit buffer and verify that we can receive in the receive
buffer if that works accurately.
Then that would confirm the worst setup is working as we expect it to.
So I'll see you in eight on the squatty.
Over here.
And I'll give this a name.
I'll call this
or call this, let's say T x buffer, because we're gonna have two of them.
And then it's gonna have, let's say, ten numbers.
And then, um, we can simply say 10, 20, 30, 40 or what is 50, 60, 70, 80, 90, 99.
Or 100, because we are dealing with a debate.
We can still go 100, right?
Okay.
And then I can see you in eight on the squatty.
And this is the rmx buffer.
This buffer would have the received data and it's going to be of the same size over here like this.
And, um, once this was done, we can proceed to initialise.
You can close this up a bit.
We can transmit that data by using deha s.p.i, transmit data.
And um, we can receive use in the whole S.P.I, receive um receive data um or you call it.
Um we can use that transmit, receive uh API both for receive and transmission.
And if we want to learn more about this, we can always take a look at the whole library, um reference
mind or we downloaded earlier.
All of this is explained and the steps to deal with each and every pair for is explained in that document.
So simplicity.
How S.P.I.
Over here.
And then the function is transmit and then receive like this on.
The first argument is the handle of the SBI H S.P.I one.
The second argument is the um is the is the transmitter buffer.
So the transmitter for what name did we give it.
We said to you X buffer over here.
You xpo for the next one is the R X buffer.
We call that uh X buffer.
So we just changes to our X and then the um the next argument, which is argument number four is the
size of the buffer.
This is ten.
And the, um, the last argument is the time out of past one hundred here, over here like this.
Because we have no S.P.I sleeve.
We're going to verify our experiment by using something known as the loop back.
We're going to connect to the measle when they Morsi line the Mizo stands for.
Must that enslave out.
And then the Mozi stands for M. Out Slavin.
We're going to connect these two lines so that we can see the data transmit from masters to slave.
Um, just it's known as the Lookback method basically.
So we're going to have a jumper wire connecting P. six and seven.
And that should be able to allow us to see that our S.P.I configuration is working right.
So let's find where P is six MPLX seven are located O come over here.
This is, uh, wiping out of the nuclear board.
If you have the disco board, you have the pinata right in there.
So you need notes, um, sort of refer to any document.
But here we have P six, MPLX seven.
So we just need a jumper to connect to be a six MPLX seven.
I'm gonna do that.
We can go ahead and build our project.
Click over here to build.
It's pulled successfully.
Click here to go to the debug.
I selected the wrong one.
Click here to go to the deponent.
Okay, I have to create a new book.
I'll come over here.
Debug us ASTM 32 Coatex M.
Okay.
So I'm going to do is at our our our X buffa to live expression, remember the X parfaits empty.
We want to know whether we can receive this data in the Erich's.
So I'll put this here like this and then I'm going to click here to run and then I'm going to pause
and then see what we have in the X buffer.
Got X upon this like this.
And, um, we have nothing in the R X buffer.
When I run again.
Pause.
We have nothing.
I stopped it.
Nessy.
If the true causes of this, if you find nothing.
It could be that the decompiled is optimizing in a way to values or you've not connected your jumper
wire properly.
So we can we can disable the optimization first.
I just realized the problem is from my jumper wire off.
Yeah.
I'll fix that.
So let's see again.
And then, um, I'll show you an image of my setup, a click over here to debug few.
Okay, so we can put a break point here.
You can basically click here.
Click the line of the wall one to place a break point.
Right.
And then we click to run so that it would stop at a break point.
This is our our expert Paphitis.
This they receive Buffa.
I remember they received barflies empty.
So if we expand now to receive Buffa has the content of the T x buffer to verify that this is really
the S.P.I transmitting the information.
I'm going to take out my jumper wire and run again.
So I'm gonna pull out my jumper wire.
And I'm going to terminate and relaunch.
Opened in.
Let's see.
We still have our break here.
I'm going to click to run.
No, there is no jumper wire.
OK, let's see.
The oryx barflies empty.
Showing is very true, meaning no data is received from TXU to Rex.
And then we're doing this, like I mention, using a method known as the loop back where we've connected
the Mousie and Mizo.
With this, we can verify our S.P.I configuration without requiring a particular S.P.I sleeve.
So this is all there is, if you have a question.
Just live in the question area.
I'll see you later.